EMNA BOUKHRIS

Software Engineering student



emna.boukhris@insat.ucar.tn

+216 52 280 012

emnahoukhris

https://www.linkedin.com /in/emna-boukhris-611014214/

Profile

I'm currently pursuing my studies at the National Institute of Applied Science and Technologies, as a Software Engineering student. I am passionate about website development and

interested in having a summer internship at your prestigious company to devote and employ all the skills I developed during my curriculum. My communication skills and attention to details are the assets that I have been able to develop and use in my previous work experiences.

Work Experience

Web Developer,

SoftParadigm | January 2023 - Present

Developed and maintained web applications using React and Node.js. Developed and maintained a database using MongoDB.

Collaborated with UX designers to create user-friendly and responsive web interfaces.

Web Developer Intern,

SoftParadigm | August 2022 - September 2022

Built a back-office admin site to manage the main web application, utilizing Angular for the front-end interface.

Developed and maintained the back-end of a web application using Spring Boot

Mobile Developer Intern,

Voguel consulting | Juin 2022 - August 2022

Designed and developed a doctor appointment mobile application using Flutter, Node Js, and Figma:

- •Implemented REST APIs for the mobile application using Node Js and Express framework.
- Utilized Figma for designing and prototyping the user interface of the mobile application and implementation of new features and UI/UX improvements.
- Conducted testing and debugging of the application to ensure functionality and resolve bugs.
- •Utilized agile methodologies, such as Scrum, to prioritize tasks and meet project deadlines.

Personal Projects

Secured Multi-user Chat Application:

python | 2023

- Developed a secure and real-time chat application that allows multiple users to communicate in a shared chat room
- Designed and implemented a SQLite database to store user information, with proper data validation and sanitization to prevent security vulnerabilities
- Used OpenSSL to establish secure connections between clients and the server, ensuring the confidentiality and integrity of communication

Skills

JAVA / OOP
JEE / Spring
JavaScript
HTML, CSS,JS
Linux
RabbitMQ
PHP/Symfony
MySQL
React /Node Js
NextJs
NestJs
Flutter
Mongodb

Design and animation tools: Photoshop illustrator Figma Blender adobe after effect

Education

software engineering cycle

2021 - Present

National Institute of Applied Science and Technology Tunisia

Preparatory cycle

2019-2021

National Institute of Applied Science and Technology Tunisia

Baccalaureate degree

2015-2019

Pioneer High school of Nabeul (majored in mathematics, graduated with honour Exam score 17.11 / 20)

Languages

Arabic French English German

Personal Qualities

Creative Adaptable Self-motivated Having an eye for detail

Hobbies

Painting Degital Art Photographie Sculpture

Responsive Event Planner website:

Angular, Nest Js ,PostgreSQL | 2023

- Developed a responsive and user-friendly event planning website that allows users to plan and manage events online .
- \bullet Utilized Angular for the front-end development and NestJS for the back-end API development, resulting in a scalable and maintainable solution .
- •Implemented authentication and authorization using PassportJS to ensure the security of the website and restrict access based on user roles.

Metro tracking mobile application:

Flutter, Firebase | 2022

- Utilized Flutter framework to develop a mobile application that tracks metro schedules in real-time.
- Implemented Google Maps API to display the metro route and location on the map.
- •Incorporated push notifications to alert users of any delays or changes in the schedule.

Responsive e-commerce website:

PHP, MySQL | 2021

- •Built a full-featured e-commerce website using PHP and MySQL as the back-end technology.
- •Incorporated a responsive design to ensure compatibility across different devices and screen sizes.
- $\bullet \mbox{Implemented}$ a shopping cart and payment gateway to allow users to make purchases.

Catalogue design for a B2B company

Adobe Illustrator ,Photoshop | 2020

• Utilized graphic design principles to create an attractive and user-friendly layout..

Activities

Freelance Artist:

• Passionate about painting and bricolage, started my own small business selling printed versions of my paintings on canvas.

Freelance Graphic designer:

• Utilizing design software such as Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to create high-quality designs for clients.

Media manger Google Developer Student Club Insat:

• Managed the media operations for the club, including photography, videography, and graphic design